<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Webapp on Arunmozhi</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/webapp/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Webapp on Arunmozhi</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>arun@arunmozhi.in (Arunmozhi)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>arun@arunmozhi.in (Arunmozhi)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Apr 2020 04:35:22 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/webapp/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Building a quick and dirty data collection app with React, Google Sheets and AWS S3</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2020/04/07/building-a-quick-and-dirty-data-collection-app-with-react-google-sheets-and-aws-s3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Apr 2020 04:35:22 +0000</pubDate><author>arun@arunmozhi.in (Arunmozhi)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2020/04/07/building-a-quick-and-dirty-data-collection-app-with-react-google-sheets-and-aws-s3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Covid-19 has created a number of challenges for the society that people are trying to solve with the tools they have. One such challenge was to create an app for data collection from volunteers for food supply requirements for their communities.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This needed a form with the following inputs:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Some text inputs like the volunteer&amp;rsquo;s name, his vehicle number, address of delivery..etc.,&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The location in geographic coordinates so that the delivery person can launch google maps and drive to the place&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;A couple of photos of the closest landmark and the building of delivery.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Multiple ready made solutions like Google Forms, Zoho Forms were attempted, but we hit a block when it came to having a map widget which would let the location to be picked manually, and uploading photos. After an insightful experience with &#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/covid19india/CovidCrowd&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CovidCrowd&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;, we were no longer in a mood to build a CRUD app with Database, servers..etc., So the hunt for low to zero maintenance solution resulted in a collection of pieces that work together like an app.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
