<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tools on Arunmozhi</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/tools/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Tools on Arunmozhi</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>arun@arunmozhi.in (Arunmozhi)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>arun@arunmozhi.in (Arunmozhi)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 13 May 2020 07:33:49 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/tools/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Thoughts on The Git Branch PR Model</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2020/05/13/thoughts-on-the-git-branch-pr-model/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 May 2020 07:33:49 +0000</pubDate><author>arun@arunmozhi.in (Arunmozhi)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2020/05/13/thoughts-on-the-git-branch-pr-model/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is just ramblings of someone who is overwhelmed when having to adapt to a new model of working with Git. There will perhaps be nothing of value here.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Git - Such a central part of everyday work. Something I learnt a decade ago. Must have spent a full month learning it well including the forking and Pull Request model from Github. Since then nothing major has changed in my workflow. It is the same routine. If it is a OpenSource project - fork the project, work on the dev branch (sometimes even master depending on how the project is maintained) and issue a pull request with the changes. If it is a team project, have a dev branch where I pushed changes. If there is a feature or refactor that will affect other people&amp;rsquo;s work, then create a branch (a feature branch) and work on the branch. Once the work is done, rebase it on the dev branch and merge it to dev.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Beautiful and clean diagrams with Keynote</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2019/09/20/beautiful-and-clean-diagrams-with-keynote/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Sep 2019 06:53:59 +0000</pubDate><author>arun@arunmozhi.in (Arunmozhi)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2019/09/20/beautiful-and-clean-diagrams-with-keynote/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Look at this flow chart like diagram. It is a really nice representation for explaining the concepts of Iterators and Generators.&#xA;[caption id=&amp;ldquo;attachment_775&amp;rdquo; align=&amp;ldquo;alignnone&amp;rdquo; width=&amp;ldquo;1272&amp;rdquo;]&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/relationships.png&#34; alt=&#34;Relationships&#34;&gt; By Vincent Driessen[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you use git, then there is a big chance you might have come across this article &#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;https://nvie.com/posts/a-successful-git-branching-model/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;A successful Git branching model&lt;/a&gt;&#xA; by the same author. There are more pretty diagrams in that post as well. For a very long time I have wondered how those diagrams are made. I decided to find out today and it turns out it was done with: &lt;strong&gt;Keynote&lt;/strong&gt; - the powerpoint equivalent in Mac.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
